paintingwithatwist.com 2019-05-01

# Painting with a Twist - Website Privacy Policy

**Effective Date: August 31, 2014**

Painting With A Twist takes your privacy very seriously. In order to protect your privacy and security, this notice provides information on our practices regarding information gathered by means of our website, paintingwithatwist.com, and how you can make choices regarding the collection and use of your information. 

###  Privacy Policy Changes 

From time to time, Painting With A Twist ("PWAT") may make changes in our privacy policy relating to our website. If we decide to change this privacy policy, those changes will be posted on this page. 

###  Information We Collect 

We collect the user's name, date of birth, gender, address, mobile phone number, email address, credit card billing address, type of credit card, credit card number, credit card security code and credit card expiration date when the user makes a reservation and pays for a PWAT class or purchases a gift certificate through our website. Information may also be collected from users when they sign up to be on our mailing list or participate in a survey. 

###  Information Automatically Collected 

The website also collects certain information automatically when a user visits our website, such as the type, IP address and operating system of the mobile device or computer being used, the identity of the user's browser, and information about the user's browser settings, how the website is used, the duration on the site and the pages visited. When you visit the website, we also may use GPS or other similar technology to determine your current physical location. No information is collected regarding the user's other online activities over time and across third-party websites, nor can parties other than PWAT collect personally identifiable information about a user's online activities by virtue of your use of the website. 

###  **Children Under 13**

PWAT does not seek to collect and does not knowingly collect any personally identifying information from anyone under the age of 13. Prior to sending any information over the Internet about themselves (for instance, names, email addresses, and phone numbers), children should always get permission from their parents. We encourage all parents to take an active interest in their children’s online activities. 

###  **How We Use Information**

PWAT gathers user information in order to improve customer and web service, including making reservations and paying for PWAT classes, purchasing gift certificates, and for usability testing purposes. We may use information collected in our marketing efforts, including sending you text, direct mail and email promotions, coupons, birthday gift certificates and other special offers. User information also may be used to analyze customer behavior based on demographics and other criteria relevant to our marketing efforts and to analyze the success rate of our marketing campaigns. GPS data may be used for geographic targeting purposes. 

###  How We Protect Information 

We have implemented security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information that we collect. In particular, the PWAT website uses a third party payment gateway, Authorize.Net, which manages the complex routing of sensitive customer information through the credit card and electronic check processing network, adhering to strict industry standards for payment processing. These standards include at present 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology for secure Internet Protocol (IP) transactions, industry leading encryption hardware and software methods and security protocols to protect customer information, and compliance with the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard. For additional information regarding the privacy of your sensitive cardholder data, please read the [Privacy Policy](https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/). 

###  Disclosure of Information to Third Parties 

We may disclose information collected from users to third parties who assist PWAT in operating the website or conducting its business, including usability testing, analyzing the success rate of marketing campaigns and advising us on marketing issues. This information is provided only after these outside parties have agreed to maintain the integrity, security and confidentiality of the personal information disclosed. PWAT also may be required to disclose certain information to comply with legal requirements, such as subpoenas, search warrants, laws, regulations or court orders as part of a legal proceeding or a law enforcement agency request. Other than the foregoing and access through Authorize.Net for purposes of credit card and electronic check processing, currently, we do not share user information collected by the website with third parties and have no plans to do so in the future. 

###  Third Party Website Links 

At the present time, the website contains links to PWAT's Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Pinterest websites and links to additional websites may be added in the future. The website also directs users to the Authorize.Net secure payment gateway in order to process users' credit card and electronic check payments. Website users should consult the Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Authorize.Net privacy policies and those of any other third-party websites to which links are provided in the future to determine their respective information practices. 

###  Your California Privacy Rights 

As part of California's "Shine the Light" law, Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, users who are residents of California are permitted to request and obtain from us, once per year, free of charge, information about any personal information that may have been disclosed to third parties in the preceding calendar year for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and are interested in making this request in writing, please submit it to: [support@paintingwithatwist.com](mailto:support@paintingwithatwist.com). 

###  Website Privacy Policy Only 

This privacy policy applies only to information collected through our paintingwithatwist.com website and not to information collected by the PWAT mobile application or offline.
